hetzner.com 2019-12-21

# Data Privacy - Hetzner Online GmbH

### Privacy Policy

#### General information

This privacy policy applies to all online services of Hetzner Online GmbH.

The controller is:

Hetzner Online GmbH  
Industriestr. 25  
91710 Gunzenhausen   
Germany

Tel.: +49 (0)9831 505-0  
Fax: +49 (0)9831 505-3

E-Mail: [info@hetzner.com](mailto:info@hetzner.com)

Registration Court Ansbach, HRB 6089  
VAT ID No. DE 812871812  
CEO: Martin Hetzner, Stephan Konvickova, Günther Müller

Margit Müller is the data protection officer, [data-protection@hetzner.com](mailto:data-protection@hetzner.com). 

#### How do you process personal data?

We save and use your personal data only to process your orders and to get in touch with you. If you subscribe to our customer newsletter, we also use your email address to send it out. We will automatically send you status messages from hetzner-status.de if you have previously changed your settings on our customer administration interface in which you request these messages. We also save and process data that job applicants provide us as part of the job application process. 

#### What categories of data do we collect?

Every time you visit our website, your IP address and other pieces of information are saved in anonymized form. If you register an account with us, your contact information will be stored. If you order products from us, your address and payment information will also be stored. 

In particular, we save the following data from you.

#### Registration data

When you register an account with us, we collect and process certain personal data from you as your registration data. For example, we need your name, address information, telephone number, payment information and your email address to process your order. If you pay using a credit card, we do not collect and store any payment information such as credit card numbers or verification codes. You disclose this information only to the respective payment service provider. One exception with credit card payments is what is known as the pseudo card number: in order for you not to have to enter your credit card information for every payment, a pseudo card number is saved for your account. The pseudo card number only enables payment for products on our website that you order using your customer account. A pseudo card number is not identical to the credit card number. We delete all your registration data either: within 24 months, as soon as you delete your user account with us, or once the statutory retention period expires. You can delete your user account with us by sending an email to [data-protection@hetzner.com](mailto:data-protection@hetzner.com) with your deletion request. The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR. 

#### Email addresses

If you subscribe to our newsletter or request that you receive automated messages from [hetzner-status.com](https://www.hetzner-status.com/), we also store your email address. We delete your email address once you delete your user account or if you unsubscribe from our newsletter.

We use the double opt-in method to ensure that you actually want to receive the newsletter. If you go through this process, you agree to receive the newsletter and to be added to the mailing list for it, and then you will receive a confirmation email that will allow you to legally confirm that you have registered for the newsletter. We will only add your name to the mailing list if you actually complete the confirmation.

We use these data exclusively for sending information that you request including information about our new offers. 

We use Newsletter2Go as our newsletter software. So if you agree to register for the newsletter, we will send your data to Newsletter2Go GmbH. Newsletter2Go is prohibited from selling your data and from using it for purposes other than sending our newsletter. Newsletter2Go is a German certified provider whom we chose because they must comply with the requirements of the EU's General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) and the German Federal Data Protection Act (BDSG).

You can find more information on Newsletter2Go here:  
<https://www.newsletter2go.com/information-for-newsletter-recipients/>

You can revoke your consent at any time to the storage of your personal data (including your email address) and to the use of your data. You can do this, for example, by clicking on the "Unsubscribe" link in the newsletter. The legal basis for processing your data for the above purpose is Art. 6 (1) lit. a or Art. 6 (1) lit. b GDPR. 

#### Server log files

Whenever you visit our websites, we automatically store certain data. This includes your IP address, type and version of the browser you use, time, date, website from which you come to our site. Your IP address is saved anonymized. You can then no longer be identified. The legal basis for this data process is Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. 

#### Forum

If you register for our online discussion forum, we save your username and email address. After you delete your account in the forum, this saved data will also be deleted. The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR. 

#### Career portal

If you send us job application documents such as your resume, references and cover letter, we will save and process these pieces of data. Application documents from job applicants that do not result in hires are deleted after 3 months. If you wish to be considered for future job openings and you consent to a longer storage period, your application documents will be deleted after 24 months. With applications that result in hires, the documents are forwarded to our HR department. The legal basis for the processing of your personal data in the job application process is primarily Section 26 of the German Data Protection Act (BDSG) in the new version, which became valid on May 25, 2018. 

#### Sweepstakes

We sometimes have sweepstakes on our websites for various occasions. If you choose to participate in the sweepstakes, we save your first and last names, your email address and, if applicable, the country you come from. We use the collected data only to process the sweepstakes. Once the sweepstakes end and the winner or winners are chosen and notified, the collected data are deleted. The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 (1) lit. a GDPR. 

#### Who we forward your data to

External service providers may have access to your data while they assist us in providing our services. In some cases, third parties such as government authorities, external consultants, or our business partners may receive your data. 

#### In particular, this may occur in the following cases:

#### Domain registration

If we register a domain for you, we provide the required data to the corresponding registration service provider. 

#### Payment via credit card:

When paying via credit card, the payment is processed by an external service provider. For credit card payments, your information is collected directly by Computop at the address Computop Wirtschaftsinformatik GmbH, Schwarzenbergstr. 4, D-96050 Bamberg. 

#### Debt collection agency

If you as a customer fail to pay your invoices on time, your necessary data are passed on to an external debt collection agency. 

#### Job application documents

If you apply for a job in Tuusula, Finland or in Munich (Unterföhring) using our career portal, we pass on your job application documents to our subsidiaries at Hetzner Finland Oy or Hetzner Cloud GmbH. We have data processing agreements with both of them. 

To manage our job applications, we use software from rexx systems GmbH. We also have a data processing agreement with this company.

#### Third countries

Data is transferred to third countries in adherence to the legally regulated admissibility requirements. We will not transfer your data to a third country if it does serve the purpose of performing our contract with you; we have no consent from you; the transfer is not necessary to assert, exercise or defend legal claims; and there are no other exceptions. We will only transfer your data to a third country if there is an adequacy decision in accordance with Art. 45 GDPR or appropriate safeguards in accordance with Art. 46 GDPR. Once such adequacy decision (regarding an adequate level of protection) is the "Privacy Shield" for the USA. For transfers to a company certified under the Privacy Shield, the data privacy level is considered essentially as adequate within the meaning of Art. 45 GDPR. However, we usually do not rely on the Privacy Shield, but rather create appropriate privacy guarantees and complete the EU standard data privacy clauses issued by the European Commission with the receiving party. Together these actions establish appropriate safeguards in accordance with Art. 46 GDPR and provide an adequate level of protection. 

#### Other categories of recipients

State authorities and courts 

#### Where do we process your data?

We process your data exclusively in our data centers in Germany and in Finland. 

#### Cookies and the right to object to direct advertising

"Cookies" are small files that are stored on a user's computer. Cookies can store different kinds of data. Cookies are primarily used to store information about users. They are stored on the users' devices during and/or after users visit a website or online store. "Temporary cookies", "session cookies", or "transient cookies" are cookies that are deleted after users leave an online store and close their browsers. With such cookies, for example, the content of a shopping basket can be stored in an online shop or a login bottleneck. However, other cookies are referred to as "permanent" or "persistent" and remain stored even after the browser is closed. For example, users' login status can be saved when they visit a shop after several days. Likewise, permanent cookies can measure the "range" of a website (where the users are geographically located) or information on the users' interests. This information is used for marketing purposes. "Third-party cookies" are cookies that are offered by the original providers (who operate the online store or website) to other parties. (If the original provider is the one using the cookies, they are often called "first-party cookies"). It is useful to know the above terms so that you understand our cookie policies and data protection agreement. If, as a Hetzner Online GmbH customer or as a visitor to our websites or interfaces, you do not wish cookies to be stored on your computer, we ask you to deactivate the corresponding option in the system settings of your browser. You can also delete stored cookies in the system settings of your browser. However, if you do these things, it will likely lead to problems when you try to use Hetzner Online GmbH websites and interfaces. If you would like to "opt out" of the use of cookies for online marketing and tracking purposes, you may be interested these two sites to help you:   
1) the US site <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>   
2) the EU site <http://www.youronlinechoices.com/>.  
Furthermore, you can deactivate cookies from being stored on your computer or device by changing your browser settings. However, if you do this, it will likely lead to problems when you try to use Hetzner Online GmbH websites, interfaces, and features on the interfaces. 

#### Social media data

#### YouTube

We integrate videos from the YouTube platform provided by Google (Google LLC, 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway, Mountain View, CA 94043, USA). Privacy Policy: <https://www.google.com/policies/privacy/>, Opt-Out: <https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>. The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. 

#### Online presence on social media

We maintain online presence on social networks and platforms in order to communicate with our customers, interested parties, and users and to inform them about our services. We use Facebook, Twitter, and Instagram, among others. When visiting each of these platforms, you as a user agree to the terms and conditions and the data processing guidelines of the corresponding operator. 

Unless stated otherwise in our data privacy notice, we process user data if users communicate with us on these social networks and platforms, e.g. publish posts on our pages or send us messages. 

We at Hetzner Online process users' data only when it is in the customer's legitimate interest for us to do so in accordance with Art. 6, (1) lit. b GDPR. As a company, we have a legal right to obtain general customer information to use in customer accounts. We also use customers' data for communication purposes. If any of the providers below request users for consent for processing their data, the legal basis for data pracessing is Art. 6 para. 1 lit. a. GDPR. 

For detailed information about the data processing operations of the providers below, as well as their opt-out options, please check the links that we have listed below. 

  * Facebook:  
Provider: Facebook Ireland Ltd., 4 Grand Canal Square, Grand Canal Harbour, Dublin 2, Irland, Joint Data Processing Agreement Data privacy agreement: <https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/> Opt-out: [https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads.](https://www.facebook.com/settings?tab=ads) Facebook has committed itself to adhering to EU data protection laws in compliance with the Privacy Shield Framework: [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000GnywAAC&status=Active)
  * Woobox:  
Provider: WOOBOX, LLC, 101 E 6th St Suite 220, Vancouver, WA 98660, Kanada  
Data protection policy: <https://woobox.com/privacy>
  * Twitter:  
Provider: Twitter Inc., 1355 Market Street, Suite 900, San Francisco, CA 94103, USA) - Data protection policy: <https://twitter.com/de/privacy> Opt-out: <https://twitter.com/personalization> Twitter has committed itself to adhering to EU data protection laws in compliance with the Privacy Shield Framework: [https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active.](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt0000000TORzAAO&status=Active)
  * Instagram:  
Provider: Instagram Inc., 1601 Willow Road, Menlo Park, CA, 94025, USA  
Data protection policy & opt-out: [http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/.](http://instagram.com/about/legal/privacy/)

#### Google Universal Analytics

On the basis of our legitimate interests (i.e. interests in analysis, optimization and commercial operation of our online offers within the meaning of Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR), we use Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Ireland Limited, Gordon House, Barrow Street, Dublin 4, Ireland ("Google"). Google uses cookies. The information generated by the cookie about the use of the online offers by the you, the user, is usually sent to a Google server in the USA and stored there. Google is certified under the Privacy Shield agreement and thus provides a safeguard in adherence to European data privacy laws ([https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active](https://www.privacyshield.gov/participant?id=a2zt000000001L5AAI&status=Active)). Google will use this information on our behalf to assess how you use our online offers, to put together reports about activities within these online offers, and to provide other services to us in connection with the usage of these online offers and the Internet use of related services. Pseudonymized usage profiles of you can be created from the processed data. We use Google Analytics in the „[Universal-Analytics](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/2790010?hl=de&ref_topic=6010376)“ version. "Universal Analytics" is a process of Google Analytics in which your user analysis is performed on the basis of your pseudonymized user ID, used to create a pseudonymized user profile of you with information on the use of various devices ("Cross-Device Tracking"). We use Google Analytics only with activated IP anonymization. This means that your IP address is shortened by Google within the member states of the European Union or in other contracting states to the Agreement on the European Economic Area. Your full IP address is sent by Google to the USA and shortened there only in exceptions. The IP address sent by the your browser is not combined by Google with your other data. You can prevent the storage of cookies by making the corresponding settings in your browser; you can also refuse the collection of data generated by the cookie and related to your use of our online offers by Google and the processing of your personal data by Google by downloading and installing the browser plugin available at the following link: <http://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout?hl=en>. Further information about data use by Google, settings, and objection options is available in Google's data privacy policy (<https://policies.google.com/technologies/ads>) and Google‘s ad settings (<https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>). Your personal data are deleted or anonymized after 14 months. The legal basis for this data processing is Art. 6 (1) lit. f GDPR. 

#### LiveZilla

We use the chat system from LiveZilla GmbH, Ekkehardstrasse 10, 78224 Singen, Germany, to provide technical support for some customers. Every time that a customer accesses this chat support service from our website, we collect and store data from the chat for web analysis and to actually operate the live chat system itself. This allows us to create user profiles with pseudonyms so that we can operate the chat and analyze visitor behavior. We can also improve our support systems, online shop, and user experience. We run Livezilla from our own servers and do not transfer your data to third parties.

If you activate live translation while using this live chat, it will integrate Google Translator. The translations generated by Google Translate should not be regarded as exact, and can sometimes contain incorrect or even offensive expressions. We do not guarantee the accuracy, reliability or currentness of the information translated by this system. Hetzner Online does not accept liability for any issues or damages that may result from possible translation errors. Furthermore, it may not be possible to translate some applications, files or elements including graphics, photos or PDFs.

Google collects, stores and processes information in order to provide users with better services. This includes, for example, not only the language used in the translation, but also the user’s entire surfing behavior.

For more information, please see [Google‘s privacy policy](https://policies.google.com/privacy?hl=en). 

#### Your rights as a "data subject"

You have the right to information about your personal data that we process. If you do not make requests for information in writing, please bear in mind that we might ask you to provide proof that you who you claim to be. Furthermore, you have a right to rectification or deletion or restriction of processing, as it is applicable to you under the law. Furthermore, in accordance with legal requirements, you have the right to object to us processing your data. You also have the right of data portability. 

#### Right to lodge a complaint

You have the right to lodge a complaint about the processing of your personal data by us to a supervisory authority for data protection. 

#### Voluntary nature of data provision

There is no statutory obligation for you to provide your data to Hetzner Online GmbH. However, you cannot use some of our services if you do not provide your data to us. Your decision to provide us with your personal data is completely voluntary.
